<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>Metadata</title>
   <body>
      <p>
         The <b>metadata tab</b> allows you to edit a file's title, description, timestamps, 
         and authorship data.
      </p>
      <img src="metadata.png" />
      <p>
         The fields available to edit are as follows:
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt>Name</dt>
            <dd>The filename displayed in-game for this game variant.</dd>
         <dt>Description</dt>
            <dd>The description displayed in-game for this game variant.</dd>
         <dt>Category Icon</dt>
            <dd>In <i>Halo: Reach</i>'s original Xbox 360 release, this icon was shown 
            in the game's menus when looking at a game variant. In all releases of 
            <i>Halo: Reach</i>, this also determines the default icon for a game 
            variant's round title card.</dd>
         <dt>Category Name</dt>
            <dd>
               <p>This determines which gametype "folder" the game variant will be placed 
               under.</p>
               <p>The original Xbox 360 release of <i>Halo: Reach</i> allowed mod 
               authors to create new folders by taking advantage of unused category 
               values, but Halo: The Master Chief Collection does not support this. If you 
               load a file that uses a custom category name, ReachVariantTool will correct 
               its category name to one that the MCC recognizes.</p>
            </dd>
         <dt>Author</dt>
            <dd>
               <p>Game variants embed the Xbox LIVE gamertag and Xbox User ID (XUID) of the 
               player who created them. However, Halo: The Master Chief Collection does not 
               make use of the embedded gamertag if you are connected to Xbox LIVE. A file 
               that has an embedded gamertag but no XUID will be displayed as having been 
               created by 343 Industries.</p>
               <p>Embedded gamertags are limited to 15 ASCII characters. The special character 
               <code>¦</code> is used to denote a game variant created by Bungie or 343 
               Industries.</p>
               <p>A button is provided to let you strip out the author XUID embedded in the 
               file. However, you are not able to associate a file with arbitrary XUIDs. If 
               you wish to add your own gamertag as an author, you'll have to resave the file 
               in-game.</p>
            </dd>
         <dt>Created At</dt>
            <dd>The date and time at which the file was created.</dd>
         <dt>Editor</dt>
            <dd>Game variants embed the Xbox LIVE gamertag and Xbox User ID (XUID) of the 
            player who edited them (if anyone did) after they were created. This data works 
            the same as authorship data.</dd>
         <dt>Edited At</dt>
            <dd>The date and time at which the file was edited.</dd>
      </dl>
      
      <h2>Notes</h2>
      <p>
         Official game variants may have descriptions that look like <code>$hr_gvar_Assault_desc</code>. 
         These descriptions are special codes that Halo: The Master Chief Collection can detect and 
         replace with its own text. 343 Industries uses this functionality to retain a greater degree 
         of control over how gametype descriptions are translated into different languages.
      </p>
   </body>
</article>