<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>Team Configuration</title>
   <body>
      <p>
         The <b>team configuration</b> page allows you to edit data related to each of 
         a game variant's eight teams.
      </p>
      <img src="options-team-specific.png" />
      <p>
         The fields available to edit are as follows:
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt>Name</dt>
            <dd>Allows you to override a team's name with custom text. The team name 
            cannot be longer than 31 characters.</dd>
         <dt>Enabled</dt>
            <dd>Controls whether this team is active, and whether players are allowed 
            to be on it.</dd>
         <dt>Set Primary Color</dt>
            <dd>If enabled, allows you to override a team's primary color. The primary 
            color is used for players' primary armor color and for the color of any 
            displayed objectives. Note that dark colors are likely to appear differently 
            in-game due to the shaders used.</dd>
         <dt>Set Secondary Color</dt>
            <dd>If enabled, allows you to override a team's secondary color. The 
            secondary color is used for players' secondary armor color.</dd>
         <dt>Set Tertiary Color</dt>
            <dd>If enabled, allows you to override a team's tertiary color. The tertiary 
            color is used as the background color for the team in the scoreboard, the 
            round card, and so on.</dd>
         <dt>Player Species</dt>
            <dd>If the <a href="options-team">general team settings</a> are set to have 
            players use team-specific species, then this option controls whether this 
            team's players spawn as Spartans or Elites.</dd>
         <dt>Fireteam Count</dt>
            <dd>Determines the number of "fireteams" on this team.</dd>
         <dt>Initial Designator</dt>
            <dd>
               <p>After each round in a match, teams will swap places; for example, in 
               offense/defense game variants with two teams, each team will take turns 
               playing the "defense" role. The game engine takes care of this behavior 
               by remapping teams internally: the gametype script always treats "Red 
               Team" (or <code>team[0]</code> internally) as Defense, and the game 
               engine just lies about which team <em>is</em> "Red Team."</p>
               <p>This option, then, determines a team's initial identity. "Which team 
               is 'Red Team,' or <code>team[0]</code>, in the first round?"</p>
            </dd>
      </dl>
   </body>
</article>