<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>General Settings</title>
   <body>
      <p>
         The <b>general settings</b> page allows you to edit basic options about a game 
         variant, such as the score to win.
      </p>
      <img src="options-general.png" />
      <p>
         The fields available to edit are as follows:
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt>Perfection Medal Enabled</dt>
            <dd>Controls whether it is possible to earn a Perfection Medal in this game 
            variant. Bungie and 343 Industries only enable this for pure Slayer variants; 
            even Flag Slayer keeps it disabled.</dd>
         <dt>Reset Players on New Round</dt>
            <dd>Supposedly resets player health and positions when a new round begins. 
            Testing is pending.</dd>
         <dt>Reset Map on New Round</dt>
            <dd>Supposedly resets a map and its contained items when a new round begins. 
            Testing is pending.</dd>
         <dt>Teams Enabled</dt>
            <dd>Controls whether teams are enabled.</dd>
         <dt>Score to Win</dt>
            <dd>The number of points that a player or team must accrue to win a round. 
            The value "unlimited" exists in place of zero (i.e. to reach it, decrease 
            the value to "1 point" and then decrease it again).</dd>
         <dt>Round Time Limit</dt>
            <dd>The maximum amount of time that a round can last. The value "no limit" 
            exists in place of zero (i.e. to reach it, decrease the value to "1 minute" 
            and then decrease it again).</dd>
         <dt>Number of Rounsd</dt>
            <dd>The maximum number of rounds that a match can have. The value "no limit" 
            exists in place of zero (i.e. to reach it, decrease the value to "1 round" 
            and then decrease it again).</dd>
         <dt>Rounds to Win</dt>
            <dd>Presumably the number of rounds that a single player or team must win 
            to win a match early. Testing is pending.</dd>
         <dt>Sudden Death Time</dt>
            <dd>How long Sudden Death lasts, in game variants that use it. Sudden 
            Death is "bonus time" granted to players if someone is near or using an 
            objective object (e.g. carrying a flag) when the round time runs out.</dd>
         <dt>Grace Period</dt>
            <dd>
               <p>How long the Grace Period lasts, in game variants that use it. If 
               the conditions needed to trigger Sudden Death stop before the Sudden Death 
               time limit is reached, then the Grace Period is how long players have to 
               reinstate those conditions before the round ends.</p>
               <p>For example, in Capture the Flag, if an attacker is standing on top of 
               the flag when the round time limit is reached, then they will be granted 
               Sudden Death time. If the attacker is killed before Sudden Death runs out, 
               then the Grace Period timer will begin. If the attackers reach the flag 
               within that time, then Sudden Death will continue from where it left off, 
               while the Grace Period resets.</p>
            </dd>
      </dl>
   </body>
</article>