<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>Social Settings</title>
   <body>
      <p>
         The <b>social settings</b> page allows you to edit settings related to players' 
         social interactions.
      </p>
      <img src="options-social.png" />
      <p>
         The fields available to edit are as follows:
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt>Enable Observers</dt>
            <dd>This option was meant to enable the ability for players to join a match 
            as spectators rather than participants. However, community reverse-engineering 
            efforts indicate that it always crashes the game.</dd>
         <dt>Team Changing</dt>
            <dd>
               <p>This option allows you to control whether players are able to change teams 
               during a match. The special value "Balancing Only" presumably enables automatic 
               team balancing; however, testing is pending.</p>
               <p>Halo: The Master Chief Collection uses a custom pause menu for all games, 
               and as of this writing, that pause menu does not allow players to change teams 
               during a match regardless of what this option has been set to.</p>
            </dd>
         <dt>Friendly Fire</dt>
            <dd>Determines whether players are able to damage and kill their teammates.</dd>
         <dt>Betrayal Booting</dt>
            <dd>If enabled, your teammates may be able to kick you from the match if you 
            kill them too many times.</dd>
         <dt>Proximity Voice</dt>
            <dd>Presumably allows you to hear enemy players' in-game voice chat if you are 
            near them; however, testing is pending.</dd>
         <dt>Don't Team-Restrict Voice Chat</dt>
            <dd>Presumably controls whether you can hear enemy players on voice chat; however, 
            testing is pending.</dd>
         <dt>Allow Dead Players to Talk</dt>
            <dd>Determines whether players can be heard on in-game voice chat while they are 
            waiting to respawn; however, testing is pending.</dd>
      </dl>
   </body>
</article>