<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>Team Settings</title>
   <body>
      <p>
         The <b>team settings</b> page allows you to edit settings related to team scoring 
         and configuration.
      </p>
      <img src="options-team.png" />
      <p>
         The fields available to edit are as follows:
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt>Team Scoring Method</dt>
            <dd>Unknown. This may be related to the oldest Halo games' options to 
            control how a team's score was computed from the scores of its players, 
            but testing is pending. <i>Halo: Reach</i> official files seem to use 
            the value 0.</dd>
         <dt>Player Species</dt>
            <dd>
               <p>Determines whether players play as Spartans or Elites. The available 
               values are:</p>
               <dl>
                  <dt>Player Preference</dt>
                     <dd>Players will spawn as the biped they've selected in their 
                     customization options.</dd>
                  <dt>All Spartans</dt>
                     <dd>Player customization will be ignored, and players will 
                     always spawn as Spartans.</dd>
                  <dt>All Elites</dt>
                     <dd>Player customization will be ignored, and players will 
                     always spawn as Elites.</dd>
                  <dt>Use Team Species</dt>
                     <dd>Player customization will be ignored, and players will spawn 
                     as the species set up in their team's individual configuration.</dd>
                  <dt>Spartans vs Elites</dt>
                     <dd>The "defense" team will be Spartans, and the "offense" team 
                     will be Elites.</dd>
               </dl>
            </dd>
         <dt>Designator Switch Type</dt>
            <dd>
               <p>This option controls how teams are remapped across rounds, but the 
               meanings of its values are unknown.</p>
               <p>After each round in a match, teams will swap places; for example, in 
               offense/defense game variants with two teams, each team will take turns 
               playing the "defense" role. The game engine takes care of this behavior 
               by remapping teams internally: the gametype script always treats "Red 
               Team" (or <code>team[0]</code> internally) as Defense, and the game 
               engine just lies about which team <em>is</em> "Red Team."</p>
               <p>This option, then, would presumably determine how teams are remapped. 
               However, it is impossible to fully test its meanings without gathering 
               up eight people to play game variants in-game.</p>
            </dd>
      </dl>
   </body>
</article>