<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>Title Update Settings</title>
   <body>
      <p>
         The <b>title update settings</b> page allows you to edit configuration data
         made available in <i>Halo: Reach</i> Title Update 1.
      </p>
      <img src="tu1.png" />
      <p>
         The fields available to edit are as follows:
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt>Shield Bleedthrough</dt>
         <dd>
            Determines whether damage "bleeds through" player shields. For example,
            if you have 5 points of shields and are hit with an attack that does 10
            points of damage, bleedthrough would result in you losing all of your
            shields as well as 5 points of health, while a lack of bleedthrough would
            result in you losing your shields but not losing any health (i.e. you
            receive 5 points of damage and the other 5 points are discarded).
         </dd>
         <dt>Activating Armor Lock doesn't shed stuck grenades</dt>
         <dd>
            Determines whether activating Armor Lock will cause you to shed any
            grenades that have been stuck to you, preventing them from killing you.
         </dd>
         <dt>Armor Lock can be stuck with plasma grenades</dt>
         <dd>
            Determines whether plasma grenades bounce off of a player that is
            currently using Armor Lock, instead of sticking to them and killing them.
         </dd>
         <dt>Enable Active Camo modifiers</dt>
         <dd>Determines whether the "Active Camo Energy Curve" values are used.</dd>
         <dt>Must have an Energy Sword to sword-block</dt>
         <dd>
            Determines whether players can survive an Energy Sword attack by using
            a melee attack with any weapon.
         </dd>
         <dt>Enable full-auto Magnum</dt>
         <dd>
            Determines whether players can fire the Magnum full-auto by holding
            the trigger.
         </dd>
         <dt>Precision Weapon Bloom</dt>
         <dd>
            Magnify or diminish the amount of bullet spread and reticle "bloom"
            applied to precision weapons when they are fired rapidly.
         </dd>
         <dt>Armor Lock Damage Drain</dt>
         <dd>
            Taking damage while using Armor Lock can drain Armor Lock's remaining
            energy.
         </dd>
         <dt>Armor Lock Damage Drain Limit</dt>
         <dd>
            The maximum amount of Armor Lock energy that can be drained by
            incoming damage.
         </dd>
         <dt>Active Camo Energy Curve Min</dt>
         <dd>Scale Active Camo's energy usage.</dd>
         <dt>Active Camo Energy Curve Max</dt>
         <dd>Scale Active Camo's energy usage.</dd>
         <dt>Magnum Damage</dt>
         <dd>A multiplier applied to the Magnum's damage output.</dd>
         <dt>Magnum Fire Delay Multiplier</dt>
         <dd>
            A multiplier applied to the delay between firing consecutive shots
            with the Magnum.
         </dd>
      </dl>
      <p>
         Additionally, there are controls at the bottom of the page that can be used to
         rapidly apply values from official game variants.
      </p>

      <h2>Imprecision</h2>
      <p>
         Due to how these values are encoded in game variant files, there are precision
         limits that come into play when saving and loading. This means that after saving
         and reloading a game variant, you may not see the exact values that you originally
         entered. The following technical details are provided for reference purposes, but
         all that one really needs to understand is that there is a margin of error that
         may range from 0.8% to 4% depending on the values one wishes to use.
      </p>
      <p>
         The precision limit, or <dfn>interval</dfn>, for Magnum options is roughly
         (10 &divide; 254), or about 0.04. The precision limit for all other options is
         roughly (2 &divide; 254), or about 0.008. Some math is done during encoding and
         decoding to ensure that the minimum and maximum values are always represented
         with exact accuracy, and to "center" other values within their allowed ranges.
         This means that the lowest non-zero value will be equal to half of the interval.
      </p>
      <p>
         As an example, the lowest values that can be encoded for non-Magnum options are:
      </p>
      <ul>
         <li>0.0000 (the minimum)</li>
         <li>0.0039 (the interval times 0.5)</li>
         <li>0.0118 (the interval times 1.5)</li>
         <li>0.0197 (the interval times 2.5)</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
         This also means that the value 1.0, used for vanilla settings, can't be represented
         exactly. The closest you can get is 1.0039, or 100.4%. Coincidentally, the margin of
         error in this case is identical for both Magnum and non-Magnum options despite the
         different intervals.
      </p>
   </body>
</article>