<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>Script Editor</title>
   <body>
      <p>
         The <b>script editor window</b> can be used to modify a gametype's script. The 
         script determines a gametype's behavior. Gametype code isn't built into the game 
         engine anymore; with <i>Halo: Reach</i>, each game variant includes its own copy 
         of a gametype's code, and that code can be modified to produce entirely new game 
         modes.
      </p>
      <img src="meta-strings.png" />
      <p>
         The pane on the left can be used to select a page to view. The bar on the bottom 
         shows how much of the available space in the game variant has been used up; it's 
         a good way to tell at a glance how "full" a file is.
      </p>
      <p>
         The pages in this window are:
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt><a href="meta-strings">Metadata Strings</a></dt>
            <dd>Edit strings used for localizing gametype categories.</dd>
         <dt><a href="string-table">All Other Strings</a></dt>
            <dd>Edit strings used by the gametype data and script.</dd>
         <dt><a href="forge-labels">Forge Labels</a></dt>
            <dd>Edit the gametype's Forge labels.</dd>
         <dt><a href="map-permissions">Map Permissions</a></dt>
            <dd>Control what maps the player can play this gametype on.</dd>
         <dt><a href="plaeyr-rating-parameters">Player Rating Parameters</a></dt>
            <dd>Control how this gametype interacts with Bungie's Arena rating system.</dd>
         <dt><a href="required-object-types">Required Object Types</a></dt>
            <dd>Specify which object types a map must define for this gametype.</dd>
         <dt><a href="script-options">Scripted Options</a></dt>
            <dd>Define which Custom Game options this gametype offers.</dd>
         <dt><a href="script-traits">Scripted Player Traits</a></dt>
            <dd>Define which player traits this gametype offers.</dd>
         <dt><a href="script-stats">Scripted Stats</a></dt>
            <dd>Define scripted scoreboard stats for this gametype.</dd>
         <dt><a href="script-widgets">Scripted HUD Widgets</a></dt>
            <dd>Define scripted HUD widgets for this gametype.</dd>
         <dt><a href="gametype-code">Gametype Code</a></dt>
            <dd>The compiler and decompiler. This is where the magic happens.</dd>
      </dl>
   </body>
</article>