<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>Player Rating Parameters</title>
   <body>
      <p>
         The <b>player rating parameters</b> script allows you to tune how the game 
         variant affects a player's Arena rating. Arena was the system that Bungie 
         designed for <i>Halo: Reach</i> in an attempt to rank players by skill. It 
         is no longer used; 343 Industries relies on TrueSkill 2, a system that uses 
         kills per minute, deaths per minute, and machine learning to determine a 
         player's skill level.
      </p>
      <img src="player-rating-parameters.png" />
      <p>
         The fields available to edit are as follows:
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt>Show Rating in Scoreboard</dt>
            <dd>Yet to be tested.</dd>
         <dt>Rating Scale</dt>
            <dd>Unknown.</dd>
         <dt>Kill Weight</dt>
            <dd>Weights the effect that kills have on the rating compared to the usual.</dd>
         <dt>Assist Weight</dt>
            <dd>Weights the effect that assists have on the rating compared to the usual.</dd>
         <dt>Betrayal Weight</dt>
            <dd>Weights the effect that betrayals have on the rating compared to the usual.</dd>
         <dt>Death Weight</dt>
            <dd>Weights the effect that deaths have on the rating compared to the usual.</dd>
         <dt>Normalize by Max Kills</dt>
            <dd>Unknown. Presumably functions as a boolean (0 or 1) despite being implemented 
            as a float.</dd>
         <dt>Base</dt>
            <dd>Unknown.</dd>
         <dt>Loss Scalar</dt>
            <dd>Unknown.</dd>
         <dt>Custom Stat 0</dt>
            <dd>Unknown. Presumably related to the first script-defined scoreboard stat.</dd>
         <dt>Custom Stat 1</dt>
            <dd>Unknown. Presumably related to the second script-defined scoreboard stat.</dd>
         <dt>Custom Stat 2</dt>
            <dd>Unknown. Presumably related to the third script-defined scoreboard stat.</dd>
         <dt>Custom Stat 3</dt>
            <dd>Unknown. Presumably related to the fourth script-defined scoreboard stat.</dd>
         <dt>Expansion 0 (reserved for future use)</dt>
            <dd>Unused.</dd>
         <dt>Expansion 1 (reserved for future use)</dt>
            <dd>Unused.</dd>
      </dl>
   </body>
</article>