<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>All Other Strings</title>
   <body>
      <p>
         The <b>string table</b> page can be used to edit all of the strings used by a 
         gametype's script. Each entry consists of several translations into different 
         languages.
      </p>
      <img src="string-table.png" />
      <p>
         You can edit an entry, create new entries, or delete entries that aren't in use 
         by the gametype script. You can also copy the English-language content of the 
         entry as either normal text, a string literal suitable for use in gametype code, 
         or an index in the string table.
      </p>
      <p>
         Internally, the string table is serialized as a <dfn>buffer</dfn> &mdash; a 
         blob of data consisting of all localizations, back to back, separated with null 
         terminators. Each localization stores the offset of the start of its string 
         content; the game loads localizations by copying data from that offset to the 
         next null terminator.
      </p>
      <p>
         The string table is subject to the following limits:
      </p>
      <ul>
         <li>There can be no more than 112 entries.</li>
         <li>The total size of the buffer, including null terminators at the ends of 
         strings, cannot be more than 19456 bytes (whether compressed or uncompressed).</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
         Compared to Bungie's own development tools, ReachVariantTool applies a minor 
         optimization: if any two localizations are exactly identical, even across 
         different entries, then they are only written into the buffer once, and the 
         two localizations share string content. Bungie only applies this optimization 
         in the case of all localizations in a single entry being exactly identical; 
         in practice this only occurs for Forge labels and team name overrides (which 
         are stored in a different string table anyway).
      </p>
   </body>
</article>