<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>String Editing and Localization</title>
   <body>
      <p>
         When editing strings in a game variant, it is usually possible to provide
         translations into multiple languages. (In some cases, this feature is not
         available due to technical limitations in the game variant file format.)
         Additionally, there is a "Library" button that you can click to access the
         <b>localized string library</b>, a collection of translations pulled from
         official Bungie content &mdash; both existing game variants and the base
         map files.
      </p>
      <img src="string-editor.png" />
      
      <h2>Round card preview</h2>
      <p>
         Many gametypes show an instructional "card" at the start of every round. The 
         text shown can be controlled <a href="script/api/player/actions/set_objective_text">through scripting</a>. 
         However, the text is truncated to a relatively short length, and it isn't 
         automatically word wrapped, so you have to insert line breaks manually.
      </p>
      <p>
         If you have the <a href="https://c20.reclaimers.net/hr/hr-ek/" target="_blank">Halo: Reach Editing Kit</a> 
         installed through Steam, and if you've properly extracted the bundled assets, 
         then you'll have a copy of Halo: Reach's main fonts on hand. ReachVariantTool 
         will detect this and allow you to open a preview window for the instructional 
         "card," by checking the "Show round card preview" checkbox.
      </p>
      <img src="string-editor-round-card-preview.png" />
      <p>
         Because this preview uses the game's own font files, it should support every 
         character set that the fonts themselves support. The game's font for body 
         text, in particular, supports a fairly wide variety of Unicode symbols:
      </p>
      <img src="string-editor-round-card-preview-unicode.png" />
      <p>
         However, <a href="script/string-special-chars">the game's special icon characters</a> 
         are not supported at this time. They aren't part of the normal font files; 
         they get baked in via some alternate system.
      </p>
      
      <h2>Localized string library</h2>
      <p>
         The string library is shown below.
      </p>
      <img src="string-library.png" />
      <p>
         The lefthand column has a list of all available strings, along with a 
         search box.
      </p>
      <p>
         The righthand column allows you to preview the text of a given string in 
         any supported language. Additionally, some strings allow you to specify 
         options. As an example, the "x Points" string allows you to substitute in 
         any number, with plurals handled for each language.
      </p>
      <p>
         Several strings also have more detailed descriptions, which may contain 
         notes about the context in which the string was used, or information 
         specific to certain languages. For example, the "Turn Clock" string in 
         Portugese is "Chess Clock," and this is noted in the description.
      </p>
   </body>
</article>