<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<script-type name="waypoint-icon">
   <friendly>Waypoint Icon</friendly>
   <blurb>An icon name suitable for use with an object waypoint, along with additional 
   data as appropriate.</blurb>
   <description>
      <p>
         The following is a list of icon names. Note that you can also use the word 
         <var>none</var> to denote no icon, or the integer index of an icon.
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt>speaker</dt>
            <dd>A loudspeaker, like that shown next to players' names in voice chat.</dd>
         <dt>dead_teammate_marker</dt>
            <dd>An "X" shape, like that used to mark where teammates have died.</dd>
         <dt>lightning_bolt</dt>
            <dd>This is supposed to be a lightning bolt, but in tests, it was blank.</dd>
         <dt>bullseye</dt>
            <dd>A bullseye.</dd>
         <dt>diamond</dt>
            <dd>A filled-in diamond shape.</dd>
         <dt>bomb</dt>
            <dd>A bomb, identical to the one used as Assault's gametype icon.</dd>
         <dt>flag</dt>
            <dd>A flag, identical to the one used as Capture the Flag's gametype icon.</dd>
         <dt>skull</dt>
            <dd>A skull, identical to the one used as Oddball's gametype icon.</dd>
         <dt>crown</dt>
            <dd>A crown, identical to the one used as King of the Hill's gametype icon.</dd>
         <dt>vip</dt>
            <dd>The gametype icon for VIP.</dd>
         <dt>padlock</dt>
            <dd>A closed padlock.</dd>
         <dt>territory_a</dt>
            <dd>If you use this value, then you must pass a number variable or integer constant 
            as an additional argument. The lowest significant digit of that numeric value will 
            be displayed as the icon (e.g. 15 will display as "5").</dd>
         <dt>territory_b</dt>
            <dd>Displays the number 2.</dd>
         <dt>territory_c</dt>
            <dd>Displays the number 3.</dd>
         <dt>territory_d</dt>
            <dd>Displays the number 4.</dd>
         <dt>territory_e</dt>
            <dd>Displays the number 5.</dd>
         <dt>territory_f</dt>
            <dd>Displays the number 6.</dd>
         <dt>territory_g</dt>
            <dd>Displays the number 7.</dd>
         <dt>territory_h</dt>
            <dd>Displays the number 8.</dd>
         <dt>territory_i</dt>
            <dd>Displays the number 9.</dd>
         <dt>supply</dt>
            <dd>Line art depicting a cube.</dd>
         <dt>supply_health</dt>
            <dd>A downward-pointing triangle outline with a circle drawn in the middle.</dd>
         <dt>supply_air_drop</dt>
            <dd>A small box suspended from a parachute.</dd>
         <dt>supply_ammo</dt>
            <dd>Three bullets lined up horizontally in a row.</dd>
         <dt>arrow</dt>
            <dd>An arrow pointing top-left. The "tail" of the arrow bends to form a circle 
            wrapping around the arrow.</dd>
         <dt>defend</dt>
            <dd>An icon indicating that a location should be defended.</dd>
         <dt>ordnance</dt>
            <dd>An icon indicating that a power weapon or vehicle is available.</dd>
         <dt>inward</dt>
            <dd>Inward-pointing triangular arrows, not unlike those displayed and animated when a 
            player is waiting to respawn on you during co-op spawning.</dd>
      </dl>
   </description>
</script-type>