<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<script-type name="widget-icon">
   <friendly>HUD Widget Icon</friendly>
   <blurb>An icon name that can be displayed on a HUD widget</blurb>
   <description>
      <p>
         The following is a list of icon names usable in HUD widgets. Note that 
         you can also use the word <var>none</var> to remove a widget's icon, 
         or the integer index of an icon.
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt>flag</dt>
            <dd>A flag, identical to the one used as Capture the Flag's gametype icon.</dd>
         <dt>slayer</dt>
            <dd>The icon for the Slayer gametype.</dd>
         <dt>oddball</dt>
            <dd>A skull, identical to the one used as Oddball's gametype icon.</dd>
         <dt>koth</dt>
            <dd>The icon for the King of the Hill gametype.</dd>
         <dt>juggernaut</dt>
            <dd>The icon for the Juggernaut gametype.</dd>
         <dt>territories</dt>
            <dd>The icon for the Territories gametype.</dd>
         <dt>assault</dt>
            <dd>The icon for the Assault gametype.</dd>
         <dt>infection</dt>
            <dd>The icon for the Infection gametype.</dd>
         <dt>vip</dt>
            <dd>The icon for the VIP gametype.</dd>
         <dt>invasion</dt>
            <dd>The icon for the Invasion gametype.</dd>
         <dt>invasion_slayer</dt>
            <dd>The icon for the Invasion Slayer gametype.</dd>
         <dt>stockpile</dt>
            <dd>The icon for the Stockpile gametype.</dd>
         <dt>action_sack</dt>
            <dd>An Action Sack icon.</dd>
         <dt>race</dt>
            <dd>The icon for the Race gametype.</dd>
         <dt>rocket_race</dt>
            <dd>The icon for the Rocket Hog Race gametype.</dd>
         <dt>grifball</dt>
            <dd>The icon for the Grifball gametype.</dd>
         <dt>soccer</dt>
            <dd>A soccer ball.</dd>
         <dt>headhunter</dt>
            <dd>The icon for the Headhunter gametype.</dd>
         <dt>crosshair</dt>
            <dd>A crosshair encircled by a spiky circular shape.</dd>
         <dt>wheel</dt>
            <dd>A tire surrounded by feathers.</dd>
         <dt>swirl</dt>
            <dd>A swirl icon &mdash; the same icon used for what is called "Insane" in legacy Reach and "Action Sack" in MCC.</dd>
         <dt>bunker</dt>
            <dd>...</dd>
         <dt>health_pack</dt>
            <dd>...</dd>
         <dt>castle_defense</dt>
            <dd>A filled-in shield shape, with the silhouette of a castle tower cut out of the middle.</dd>
         <dt>return</dt>
            <dd>An arrow pointing bottom-left. The tail of the arrow bends to the left and then around 
            the arrow, forming a box which encloses the arrow.</dd>
         <dt>shapes</dt>
            <dd>Line art of 3D geometric shapes.</dd>
         <dt>cartographer</dt>
            <dd>The insignia for the Silent Cartographer.</dd>
         <dt>eight_ball</dt>
            <dd>A drawing of an eight ball, of the variety seen in billiards.</dd>
         <dt>noble</dt>
            <dd>The Noble Team insignia.</dd>
         <dt>covenant</dt>
            <dd>A Covenant insignia.</dd>
         <dt>attack</dt>
            <dd>A rounded diamond shape, inside of which is a downward-pointing arrow. Beneath the 
            arrow, between it and the diamond, is a bent line following the diamond's shape.</dd>
         <dt>defend</dt>
            <dd>...</dd>
         <dt>ordnance</dt>
            <dd>...</dd>
         <dt>circle</dt>
            <dd>A downward-pointing triangle outline with a small circle drawn inside.</dd>
         <dt>recon</dt>
            <dd>A rounded rectangle, with a targeting reticle drawn inside: four corners of a 
            non-rounded rectangle, and a plus symbol at the center.</dd>
         <dt>recover</dt>
            <dd>...</dd>
         <dt>ammo</dt>
            <dd>...</dd>
         <dt>skull</dt>
            <dd>A skull icon, of the variety seen in Campaign and Firefight.</dd>
         <dt>forge</dt>
            <dd>The icon for Forge: a hammer (more like a gavel, actually) slamming down onto 
            an anvil, emitting stylized sparks.</dd>
      </dl>
   </description>
</script-type>