<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>Main Window</title>
   <body>
      <p>
         The <b>main window</b> offers access to <i>Halo: Reach</i>'s most basic settings. Its 
         exact contents will vary depending on the type of file you load; this article describes 
         the contents for Firefight game variants.
      </p>
      <img src="scenario.png" />
      <p>
         The pane on the left can be used to select a page to view.
      </p>
      <p>
         The pages in this window are:
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt><a href="metadata">Metadata</a></dt>
            <dd>Edit a game variant's title, description, and category.</dd>
         <dt><a href="scenario">Firefight Settings</a></dt>
            <dd>Edit basic settings related to Firefight.</dd>
         <dt><a href="lives">Player Lives</a></dt>
            <dd>Edit settings related to players' extra lives.</dd>
         <dt><a href="options-respawn">Spartan and Elite Respawn Settings</a></dt>
            <dd>Edit respawn times. Spartan and Elite players can be given different settings.</dd>
         <dt>Spartan and Elite Respawn Traits</dt>
            <dd>Edit the <a href="traits">traits</a> that players are briefly given after they 
            respawn. Spartan and Elite players can be given different settings.</dd>
         <dt>Base Spartan Traits</dt>
            <dd>Edit the <a href="traits">traits</a> applied to all player-controlled Spartans.</dd>
         <dt>Base Elite Traits</dt>
            <dd>Edit the <a href="traits">traits</a> applied to all player-controlled Elites.</dd>
         <dt>Base Wave Traits</dt>
            <dd>Edit the <a href="traits-wave">traits</a> applied to all NPCs.</dd>
         <dt><a href="round">Round 1</a></dt>
         <dt>Round 2</dt>
         <dt>Round 3</dt>
            <dd>Edit the settings for each round.</dd>
         <dt><a href="bonus-wave">Bonus Wave</a></dt>
            <dd>Edit settings for the Bonus Wave.</dd>
         <dt><a href="custom-skull">Red Skull</a></dt>
         <dt>Blue Skull</dt>
         <dt>Yellow Skull</dt>
            <dd>Edit the effects of each Custom Skull.</dd>
         <dt><a href="options-general">General Settings</a></dt>
            <dd>Edit basic settings related to scoring and time limits.</dd>
         <dt><a href="options-social">Social Settings</a></dt>
            <dd>Edit settings related to chat and teamplay.</dd>
         <dt>Base Player Traits</dt>
            <dd>Edit the baseline <a href="traits">traits</a> that apply to all players. These 
            are overridden by Base Spartan Traits and Base Elite Traits.</dd>
         <dt><a href="options-team">Team Settings</a></dt>
            <dd>Edit basic settings and internal configuration for teams.</dd>
         <dt><a href="options-team-specific">Team #</a></dt>
            <dd>Edit internal configuration for each individual team.</dd>
         <dt><a href="options-loadout">Loadout Settings</a></dt>
            <dd>Edit baseline settings for loadouts.</dd>
      </dl>
      
      <h2>Sections hidden by default</h2>
      <p>
         Firefight files contain the same set of Custom Game options as normal Multiplayer 
         game variants, but not all of these options are functional. By default, 
         ReachVariantTool will hide Firefight settings that are known to be non-functional. 
         Those settings include the following sections:
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt>Map and Game Settings</dt>
            <dd>Edit settings related to the map and powerups.</dd>
         <dt>Red Powerup Traits</dt>
            <dd>Edit the <a href="traits">traits</a> conferred by the Overshield powerup.</dd>
         <dt>Blue Powerup Traits</dt>
            <dd>Edit the <a href="traits">traits</a> conferred by the Active Camo powerup.</dd>
         <dt>Yellow Powerup Traits</dt>
            <dd>Edit the <a href="traits">traits</a> conferred by the Custom Powerup.</dd>
         <dt><a href="options-loadout">Tier 2 and 3 Loadouts</a></dt>
            <dd>Edit settings for loadouts.</dd>
      </dl>
   </body>
</article>