<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>Map and Game Settings</title>
   <body>
      <p>
         The <b>map and game settings</b> page allows you to edit settings related to what 
         objects can spawn on the map, and how powerups work.
      </p>
      <p>
         The fields available to edit are as follows:
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt>Indestructible Vehicles</dt>
            <dd>Controls whether vehicles can be destroyed.</dd>
         <dt>Vehicle Set</dt>
            <dd>Controls which types of vehicles can spawn on the map. Spawn points for 
            ineligible vehicles may be altered to produce an eligible vehicle, or may 
            produce nothing, depending on the chosen vehicle set.</dd>
      </dl>
      
      <h2>Fields hidden by default</h2>
      <p>
         Firefight files contain the same set of Custom Game options as normal Multiplayer 
         game variants, but not all of these options are functional. By default, 
         ReachVariantTool will hide or grey out Firefight settings that are known to be 
         non-functional. Those settings include:
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt>Grenades on Map</dt>
            <dd>Controls whether grenades can spawn on the map. This probably would 
            work if any Firefight maps had pre-placed grenades.</dd>
         <dt>Shortcuts on Map</dt>
            <dd>Unknown.</dd>
         <dt>Armor Abilities on Map</dt>
            <dd>Controls whether Armor Ability pickups can spawn on the map. This probably 
            would work if any Firefight maps had pre-placed Armor Ability pickups.</dd>
         <dt>Powerups on Map</dt>
            <dd>Controls whether powerups can spawn on the map. This probably would 
            work if any Firefight maps had pre-placed powerups.</dd>
         <dt>Turrets on Map</dt>
            <dd>Controls whether turrets can spawn on the map.</dd>
         <dt>Weapon Set</dt>
            <dd>Controls which types of weapons can spawn on the map. This probably would 
            work if any Firefight maps had pre-placed weapons.</dd>
         <dt>Red Powerup Duration</dt>
            <dd>Controls how long the player has Red Powerup Traits after picking up 
            an Overshield powerup. Since powerups don't appear on Firefight maps, this 
            setting is unused here.</dd>
         <dt>Blue Powerup Duration</dt>
            <dd>Controls how long the player has Blue Powerup Traits after picking up 
            an Active Camo powerup. Since powerups don't appear on Firefight maps, this 
            setting is unused here.</dd>
         <dt>Custom Powerup Duration</dt>
            <dd>Controls how long the player has Yellow Powerup Traits after picking up 
            a Custom Powerup. Since powerups don't appear on Firefight maps, this 
            setting is unused here.</dd>
      </dl>
   </body>
</article>