<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>Firefight Settings</title>
   <body>
      <p>
         The <b>Firefight settings</b> page allows you to control overall scenario settings 
         for Firefight.
      </p>
      <img src="scenario.png" />
      <p>
         The fields available to edit are as follows:
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt>Wave Limit</dt>
            <dd>
               <p>
                  This is the maximum number of waves that the Firefight match is allowed to 
                  have per <a href="/concepts/firefight#overall-match-flow">turn</a>. This 
                  value should include bonus waves even if you have disabled them in 
                  <a href="bonus-wave">their settings</a>.
               </p>
               <p>
                  Text below the input control will translate the raw number of waves to a 
                  number of sets, rounds, and waves.
               </p>
            </dd>
         <dt>Hazards</dt>
            <dd>Controls whether map-specific Hazards will appear on the map. These can 
            include: Banshees (as on Holdout); Drop Pods filled with Brutes (armed with 
            Concussion Rifles), Grunts (armed with Fuel Rod Guns), or Elite Ultras; 
            and Wraiths.</dd>
         <dt>Weapon Drops</dt>
            <dd>Controls whether UNSC heavy weapons are air-dropped onto the map at the 
            start of each round.</dd>
         <dt>Ammo Crates</dt>
            <dd>Determines whether UNSC ammo crates spawn on the map. Ammo crates will refill 
            any UNSC non-power weapons when a player walks up to them.</dd>
         <dt>Generator Count</dt>
            <dd>Determines how many generators are on the map. Set this to zero (disabled) 
            to turn Generator Defense off.</dd>
         <dt>Generator Fail Condition</dt>
            <dd>Controls whether Spartans lose the match if they lose all generators, or 
            just one.</dd>
         <dt>Generator Spawn Locations</dt>
            <dd>Controls which of a map's three generator spawn locations are used, when 
            fewer than three generators are present.</dd>
         <dt>Force Reach Beta PvP ("Network Test 1")</dt>
            <dd>This setting was made available in the Master Chief Collection's mid-July 2023 
            update. When enabled, it turns on all of the unique features for the Halo: Reach 
            Beta's "Network Test 1" Generator Defense mode: all NPC AI are disabled, so the 
            mode becomes exclusively PvP, and some other changes (e.g. to Health Pack spawning) 
            are made as well.</dd>
         <dt>Unknown B</dt>
            <dd>Unknown. Possibly unused.</dd>
         <dt>Bonus Target</dt>
            <dd>Unused. A quantity of points. This value is exposed to the HaloScript code that 
            powers Firefight (<code>survival_mode_get_bonus_target</code>), but the script 
            doesn't actually use it.</dd>
         <dt>Unknown D</dt>
            <dd>Unknown. Possibly unused.</dd>
      </dl>
   </body>
</article>