<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>Wave Traits</title>
   <body>
      <p>
         The <b>wave traits</b> page allows you to edit the traits for NPCs. Note that 
         these traits are far less varied than <a href="traits">player traits</a>, and 
         mainly concern AI behavior.
      </p>
      <img src="traits-wave.png" />
      <p>
         The fields available to edit are as follows:
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt>Damage Modifier</dt>
            <dd>Scales the amount of damage that NPC weapons and melees do.</dd>
         <dt>Damage Resistance</dt>
            <dd>Scales the amount of damage that NPCs can withstand. Note that this also 
            scales the strength of breakable enemy armor, such as Grunt Ultras' helmets.</dd>
         <dt>Vision</dt>
            <dd>
               <p>Controls how likely an NPC is to notice an enemy within its line of sight.</p>
               <p>The "Nearsighted" option reduces an NPC's sight range to 20% and reduces 
               their field of view (i.e. vision cone angle) to 80%. The "Eagle Eye" option 
               boosts their sight range to 150% and their field of view to 120%.</p>
            </dd>
         <dt>Hearing</dt>
            <dd>Controls how likely an NPC is to notice enemies that are making noise. 
            The "Sharp" option doubles the NPC's hearing range.</dd>
         <dt>Luck</dt>
            <dd>
               <p>Controls how likely an NPC is to dodge grenades and needles, versus how 
               likely an NPC Grunt is to flee or attempt a suicide bombing.</p>
               <dl>
                  <dt>Unlucky</dt>
                     <dd>Never evades fire, dives away from grenades, or attempts a suicide 
                     bombing. Always retreats after diving. Never goes berserk after shields 
                     pop. Leaders don't go berserk after their followers are all killed.</dd>
                  <dt>Normal</dt>
                     <dd>No changes are made to the base AI data.</dd>
                  <dt>Lucky</dt>
                     <dd>75% more likely to evade fire and dive away from grenades. Never 
                     retreats after diving. The delays between successive melee attacks, 
                     and successive grenade throws, are halved. Twice as likely to melee.</dd>
                  <dt>Leprechaun</dt>
                     <dd>Evades fire and dives away from grenades as often as is physically 
                     possible. Never retreats after diving. Always attempts a suicide bombing 
                     when "broken." Always retreats when their leader dies. Always goes berserk 
                     when their shields pop. Leaders always go berserk when their followers are 
                     all killed. The delays between successive melee attacks, and successive 
                     grenade throws, are halved. Always melees when it is possible to do so.</dd>
               </dl>
            </dd>
         <dt>Shootiness</dt>
            <dd>
               <p>Controls NPCs' accuracy and tendency to fire excess shots.</p>
            </dd>
         <dt>Grenades</dt>
            <dd>Controls how often NPCs use grenades. The "Catch" option significantly 
            increases the NPC's likelihood of throwing grenades, halves the delay between 
            successive grenade throws, and doubles grenades' outbound velocity.</dd>
         <dt>Don't Drop Equipment on Death</dt>
            <dd>If this option is enabled, then NPCs will not drop weapons or grenades when 
            they die.</dd>
         <dt>Assassination Immunity</dt>
            <dd>Controls whether NPCs are immune to instant-kill melees to the back, and 
            to special finishing moves (which players will not be allowed to perform).</dd>
         <dt>Headshot Immunity</dt>
            <dd>Controls whether NPCs are immune to instant-kill headshots.</dd>
      </dl>
      <p>
         All exact stats for AI changes are based on examination of the game data using the 
         <i>Halo: Reach</i> Editing Kit. Not all behaviors (e.g. "going berserk") may apply 
         to all NPC types.
      </p>
      
      <h2>Under the hood</h2>
      <p>The effects of the Vision, Hearing, Luck, and Grenades options are all defined in 
      the <code>globals\ai_globals.ai_globals</code> tag.</p>
      <p>The effects of the Shootiness option appear to be defined on <code>character</code> 
      tags. The <code>tags/ai/generic.character</code> tag defines defaults that can be 
      overridden by each individual NPC type. Within a character tag, "firing patterns" 
      (with the same names as the Shootiness option values) can be defined per weapon, and 
      the parameters associated with a firing pattern include:</p>
      <ul>
         <li>How many times per second they pull the trigger</li>
         <li>How long each burst they fire is</li>
         <li>How long they wait between bursts</li>
         <li>The distance by which they are likely to miss their target when they 
         begin firing a burst (such that they have to correct their aim over time)</li>
         <li>The maximum angle by which they can miss their target when they begin 
         firing a burst</li>
         <li>How well they can track a moving target, in terms of how well they 
         adjust their aim after they begin firing a burst</li>
         <li>How well they can lead a moving target, predicting its movement</li>
      </ul>
   </body>
</article>