<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>Bipeds and items</title>
   <body>
      <p>
         A "biped" is any character that a player can theoretically control. This includes 
         typical Spartans and Elites, but it also includes Monitors and spawned holograms. 
         This article is an overview of several aspects of bipeds that can be relevant when 
         writing scripts.
      </p>
      
      <h2><a name="positioning">Positioning</a></h2>
      <p>
         When attempting to attach objects to a biped, or position objects relative to a 
         biped, it is important to understand the nuances of how bipeds' positions work.
      </p>
      <p>
         A "grounded" biped &mdash; that is, one which walks on the ground, like Spartans 
         and Elites &mdash; will have a rotation that does <em>not</em> match the direction 
         that its player is looking in. Rather, the position and rotation of a biped is 
         more closely linked to its physics and animation; typically, a biped will be 
         facing toward whatever direction its legs are pointing in, though its facing 
         direction can change rapidly as the biped switches between strafing and non-strafing 
         animations.
      </p>
      <p>
         A "grounded" biped's rotation will more accurately reflect the player's camera 
         when the biped is in midair, but it still won't match up in real-time. If the 
         player rapidly looks to the side while in midair, the biped's rotation will 
         animate in that direction, possibly at a slower speed than the player's camera 
         speed.
      </p>
      <p>
         "Grounded" bipeds are always considered upright; even if the player is looking 
         upward or downward, the biped's "forward" direction will always be level with 
         flat ground.
      </p>
      
      <h2><a name="attachment">Attachment</a></h2>
      <p>
         A biped's held items are attached to the biped; the object attachment system 
         that Megalo has access to appears to be the same system that the game uses 
         internally for equipped items. Similarly, a biped occupying a vehicle is 
         attached to that vehicle.
      </p>
   </body>
</article>