<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>Aliases</title>
   <body>
      <p>
         Megalo only supports a limited number of variables; however, you can define 
         <dfn>aliases</dfn>, or custom names, for each variable. Once defined, an 
         alias can be used in any context where the original variable could be used.
      </p>
      <pre>
         alias is_zombie = player.number[0]
         
         for each player do
            if current_player.is_zombie == 1 then
               --
               -- ...
               --
            end
         end
      </pre>
      <p>
         You can also alias certain values that are specific to argument types, such as 
         object types:
      </p>
      <pre>
         alias temp_int_00   = global.number[0]
         alias objective_obj = flag
         
         for each team do
            alias created = temp_int_00
            --
            created = 0
            for each object with label "ctf_return" do
               if created == 0 and current_object.team == current_team then
                  current_object.place_at_me(objective_obj, none, never_garbage_collect, 0, 0, 0, none)
                  created = 1
               end
            end
         end
      </pre>
      
      <h2>Features of aliases</h2>
      
      <h3>Absolute or relative</h3>
      <p>
         Aliases can be "absolute" or "relative." An absolute alias refers to an integer 
         constant or to a global value, while a relative alias refers to a nested variable.
      </p>
      <pre>
         alias absolute_constant = 5
         
         alias absolute_variable = global.number[0]
         
         if absolute_variable == 1 then
            -- ...
         end
         
         --
         -- Relative alias:
         --
         
         alias relative_variable = player.number[0]
         
         for each player do
            if current_player.relative_variable == 1 then
               -- ...
            end
         end
      </pre>
      <p>
         In that code example, we define <var>relative_variable</var> as an alias that 
         can be accessed on all player-type variables; the alias refers to any given 
         player's nested <code>number[0]</code> variable.
      </p>
      
      <h3>Scoping</h3>
      <p>
         Aliases are <dfn>block-scoped</dfn>. This means that they only exist inside of 
         the block of code they were defined in; they <dfn>go out of scope</dfn> &mdash; 
         they stop existing &mdash; past the end of that block.
      </p>
      <pre>
         -- Let's mark a variable for temporary use, with an alias.
         alias temporary_number_variable = global.number[0]
         
         for each player do
            if current_player.killer_type_is(kill) then
               alias death_type = temporary_number_variable
               
               death_type = current_player.get_death_damage_type()
               if death_type == enums.damage_reporting_type.dmr then
                  --
                  -- (current_player) was killed with a DMR.
                  --
               end
            end
         end
         
         -- The "death_type" alias isn't available here, so it doesn't make a mess.
      </pre>
      <p>
         Aliases that are defined outside of all blocks will never go out of scope; they 
         are always <dfn>in-scope</dfn> &mdash; always available from the current scope.
      </p>
      
      <h3>Shadowing</h3>
      <p>
         Aliases <dfn>shadow</dfn> each other. That is: if you define multiple aliases 
         with the same name, the most recently defined one (i.e. the one furthest down 
         in the code) will prevent access to the others.
      </p>
      <pre>
         global.number[0] = 3
         
         alias example_alias = 1
         alias example_alias = 2
         alias example_alias = 3 -- This alias shadows the others...
         
         if global.number[0] == example_alias then
            -- ...so code in this block will run.
         end
      </pre>
      <p>
         Shadowing is affected by scoping:
      </p>
      <pre>
         alias example = 1
         
         for each player do
            alias example = 5 -- Shadows the other alias.
            
            current_player.number[0] = example
         end
         -- The "shadowing" alias isn't in-scope anymore. The alias that was once shadowed 
         -- is now available: `example` is now `1`.
      </pre>
      
      <h2>Allocation to aliases</h2>
      <p>
         Variables can be <dfn>allocated</dfn> to aliases dynamically. That is: you can 
         ask for a variable of a given type, without having to manually specify the 
         variable's index.
      </p>
      <pre>
         alias absolute_alias = allocate global.number
         
         alias relative_alias = allocate player.number
      </pre>
      <p>
         For these alias declarations, ReachVariantTool will look for any variable of 
         the requested type that is not already pointed to by an alias that is in-scope, 
         and use the first such variable that it finds. If no such variables remain (i.e. 
         every variable of the type you've asked for is already aliased), then a compiler 
         error will occur.
      </p>
      <pre>
         alias some_alias = global.number[0]
         
         -- The `global.number[0]` variable is referred to by another alias, so while 
         -- there's no guarantee that `example` will refer to any specific global.number 
         -- variable, there *is* a guarantee that it *won't* refer to `global.number[0]`.
         alias example  = allocate global.number
      </pre>
      <p>
         You can also allocate <a href="script/api/ns_temporaries.html">temporary variables</a> using 
         a special syntax:
      </p>
      <pre>
         alias my_temporary_variable = allocate temporary number
      </pre>
      
      <h3>Collision warnings</h3>
      <p>
         If you accidentally point an alias at a variable that was allocated to another 
         alias, the compiler will warn you.
      </p>
      <pre>
         -- Assume this is the only code in the entire script.
         
         alias example_allocated = allocate global.number
         -- Because no other global.number variables have been aliased, this will be 
         -- the global.number[0] variable.
         
         alias example_explicit = global.number[0]
         -- This will generate a warning. The compiler will tell you that the other 
         -- alias, `example_allocated`, just happened to end up using the variable 
         -- that you're now also assigning to this alias.
         
         alias example_borrowed = example_allocated
         -- This does not generate a warning. You clearly intend for both of these 
         -- aliases to point to the same variable, because you're making the one 
         -- alias point to the other alias.
      </pre>
      <p>
         The reason this warning exists is because if you run into this situation, it 
         likely won't be on purpose. While it <em>is</em> possible to predict which 
         variable will be allocated to any given alias, the whole point of allocating 
         variables to aliases (as opposed to choosing variables manually) is that you 
         shouldn't actually have to care what variable ends up in that alias.
      </p>
      <p>
         If you get this warning, you would generally want to either allocate variables 
         to aliases after all manually-set aliases, or change the manually-set alias to 
         one that allocates a variable.
      </p>
      
      <h3>User-defined functions</h3>
      <p>
         Allocation-to-aliases works inside of user-defined functions; however, there 
         are technical limitations that arise as a result of flaws in ReachVariantTool's 
         design.
      </p>
      <p>
         If a user-defined function is in scope, and the function definition contains 
         aliases, then none of the aliased variables can be allocated to a new alias 
         until the function goes out of scope. This is an exception to the normal rules 
         for allocation-to-aliases, and is a safety measure to prevent variable collisions 
         in situations like the following:
      </p>
      <pre>
         function some_helper_function()
            alias local_variable = allocate temporary number
            
            local_variable = 5
         end
         
         alias some_important_variable = allocate temporary number
         some_important_variable = 1
         
         some_helper_function()
         
         if some_important_variable != 1 then
            game.show_message_to(all_players, none, "Oh no!")
         end
      </pre>
      <p>
         In that code snippet, we allocate a temporary variable to an alias, <var>local_variable</var>, 
         inside the function. However, once we reach the end of the function body, that alias is, 
         technically, out of scope. The only way to prevent <var>some_important_variable</var> from 
         accidentally reusing that same variable &mdash; leading to a variable collision, where 
         calling the function accidentally <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clobbering" target="_blank">clobbers</a> 
         data in the caller &mdash; is to make it so that variables that are aliased in any in-scope 
         function are reserved.
      </p>
      <p>
         This is a very imperfect workaround. In the following situation, for example, both of the 
         user-defined functions are forced to use separate variables even though there's no risk 
         of a collsiion between them (because neither function calls the other):
      </p>
      <pre>
         function first()
            alias first_alias = allocate temporary number
         end
         
         function second()
            alias second_alias = allocate temporary number
         end
      </pre>
      <p>
         This is all necessary because of technical limitations in ReachVariantTool's design: it 
         only reads your code once, and it never backtracks to revise what it's compiled. When it 
         sees the definition of <code>second_alias</code>, it hasn't yet read the rest of <code>second()</code>, 
         so it doesn't know for sure whether <code>second()</code> calls <code>first()</code>; it only 
         knows that <code>second()</code> <em>can</em> call <code>first()</code>, so it gives <code>second()</code> 
         a separate variable in order to avoid any potential collisions.
      </p>
      <p>
         A side-effect of this is that if you define a function outside of any other block, and that 
         function allocates temporary variables, then you will accidentally reserve those variables 
         for the entire rest of the script, preventing any other code from reusing them. One fix for  
         this is to nest your functions in whatever blocks of code actually use them.
      </p>
   </body>
</article>