<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>Variable declarations</title>
   <body>
      <p>
         Variable declarations allow you to specify a variable's networking priority and its 
         initial value. They look like this:
      </p>
      <pre>
         declare SOME_VARIABLE
         declare SOME_VARIABLE = SOME_NUMBER
         declare SOME_VARIABLE with network priority SOME_PRIORITY
         declare SOME_VARIABLE with network priority SOME_PRIORITY = SOME_NUMBER
      </pre>
      <p>
         When specifying the variable to declare, you are allowed to use an <a href="alias">alias</a>.
      </p>
      <p>
         Only number and timer variables can be given initial values. These values can be any 
         number except for another variable. If you do not specify an initial value (or if you 
         don't declare the variable at all), then the initial value used is zero.
      </p>
      <p>
         All variable types except for timers can have a networking priority set. The network 
         priority values are:
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt>low</dt>
            <dd>Testing has established that low-priority variables can survive a host migration. 
            If you don't specify a networking priority for a variable, this is used as the 
            default.</dd>
         <dt>high</dt>
            <dd>Testing has established that high-priority variables can survive a host migration. 
            If you wish to display a player variable in the UI, it must be high-priority.</dd>
         <dt>local</dt>
            <dd>Variables with this network priority aren't sent over the network at all. This 
            is a good thing to use for temporary variables that are just used to do quick tasks, 
            like computing a number to be stored elsewhere.</dd>
      </dl>
      <p>
         Declaring a variable multiple times generates a compiler warning if the declarations 
         don't conflict with each other or contain redundant information (e.g. multiple initial 
         values), or a compiler error otherwise.
      </p>
      
      <h2>Temporary variables</h2>
      <p>
         Temporary variables do not need to be declared, and cannot be given an initial value or 
         a networking priority. Attempting to declare them is a warning, unless you also specify 
         an initial value or networking priority, in which case it's an error.
      </p>
   </body>
</article>