<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>For-loops</title>
   <body>
      <p>
         A "for-each loop" allows you to execute a piece of code multiple times, with it 
         able to access and process some object in a collection each time. Megalo offers 
         a few types of for-each loops:
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt>for each object</dt>
            <dd>Process every object on the map.</dd>
         <dt>for each object with label ...</dt>
            <dd>Process every object on the map that matches a given Forge label.</dd>
         <dt>for each player</dt>
            <dd>Process every player currently participating in the match.</dd>
         <dt>for each player randomly</dt>
            <dd>Process every player in a random order.</dd>
         <dt>for each team</dt>
            <dd>Process every team defined in the gametype, as well as Neutral Team.</dd>
      </dl>
      
      <h2>For each object</h2>
      <p>
         This block loops over every object on the map. You can access the object being 
         processed using <var>current_object</var>.
      </p>
      
      <h2>For each object with label</h2>
      <p>
         This block loops over every object on the map that matches a given Forge label. 
         The label can be specified as a string literal containing the label's name, or as 
         an integer constant denoting the index of the Forge label in the game variant's 
         Forge label list. You can access the object being processed using 
         <var>current_object</var>.
      </p>
      
      <h2>For each player</h2>
      <p>
         This block loops over every player currently in the match. You can access the 
         player being processed using <var>current_player</var>.
      </p>
      
      <h2>For each player randomly</h2>
      <p>
         This block loops over every player currently in the match, in a random order. 
         You can access the player being processed using <var>current_player</var>.
      </p>
      
      <h2>For each team</h2>
      <p>
         This block loops over every team currently in the match. You can access the 
         team being processed using <var>current_team</var>.
      </p>
   </body>
</article>