<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<article>
   <title>Basic syntax</title>
   <body>
      <h2>Statements</h2>
      <p>
         Statements in a Megalo script can be divided into three categories: conditions, actions, 
         and blocks.
      </p>
      
      <h3>Blocks</h3>
      <p>
         The following block types are available:
      </p>
      <dl>
         <dt>do ... end</dt>
            <dd>A generic block.</dd>
         <dt>enum ... end</dt>
            <dd>An <a href="enum">enum definition</a></dd>
         <dt>for ... do ... end</dt>
            <dd>A piece of code which should be executed multiple times in a row, 
            with specific information made available each time.</dd>
         <dt>function ... end</dt>
            <dd>A user-defined function which can be "called," or triggered to run, 
            from different parts of the script. <a href="function">More details here.</a></dd>
         <dt>if ... altif ... alt ... end</dt>
            <dd>A piece of code which should execute if specific conditions are met. 
            <a href="if">More details here.</a></dd>
      </dl>
      <p>
         Top-level blocks (that is, blocks not nested inside of other blocks) can be prefixed 
         with <a href="events">event name</a>.
      </p>
      
      <h3>Actions</h3>
      <p>
         An action is any statement that doesn't appear in an if-block's condition list. Actions 
         can begin with a keyword, or they can take one of the following forms:
      </p>
      <ul>
         <li><code>function()</code></li>
         <li><code>variable = function()</code></li>
         <li><code>variable = value</code></li>
      </ul>
      <p>
         This particular Megalo dialect does not support expressions; for example, the following 
         statement is interpreted as an assignment followed by an unexpected operator:
      </p>
      <pre>
         a = b + c
         
         -- The above is interpreted as two statements: "a = b" and "+ c".
      </pre>
      
      <h3>Conditions</h3>
      <p>
         Conditions are terms in an if-block's condition list. They must take one of the following 
         two forms:
      </p>
      <ul>
         <li><code>function()</code></li>
         <li><code>value == other_value</code></li>
      </ul>
      <p>
         Conditions can be prefixed with the word <var>not</var> to invert them. Conditions must be 
         separated from each other with the word <var>or</var> or the word <var>and</var>.
      </p>
      
      <h2>Variables</h2>
      <p>
         Megalo supports the following variable types:
      </p>
      <ul>
         <li><a href="api/number">Number</a></li>
         <li><a href="api/object">Object</a></li>
         <li><a href="api/player">Player</a></li>
         <li><a href="api/team">Team</a></li>
         <li><a href="api/timer">Timer</a></li>
      </ul>
      <p>
         Variables are either global or nested. There is one "global" set of variables that is 
         accessible at all times, and every object, player, and team is also capable of holding 
         its own set of variables.
      </p>
   </body>
</article>